

# **Ozan** Biber

**Date of birth:** 09/03/1994 | **Nationality:** Turkish | **Gender** Male | (+90) 5064015694 |

oznbiber@gmail.com | Skype: ozan.biber |

Dedebaşı Mahallesi 6113 Sokak No:6 Kat:5 Daire:11, Karşıyaka, 35560, İzmir, Turkey

About me: I am a versatile software engineer with two years of experience in web based applications with various technologies. Experienced with; - Full-stack web app/service/ API development (Spring, Hibernate, REST/JSON, SOAP/XML etc.) - Unit and integration testing - Object-Oriented Design and Programming, well-known patterns, architectures - Scrum/Agile methodologies

## WORK EXPERIENCE

01/08/2019 – CURRENT – İzmir, Turkey **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER –** YAŞAR BILGI

- Working as a full-stack developer on company's multiple different in-house projects based on Java/Spring Framework.
- Analyzing and developing new features, fixing bugs, enhancing code quality, general efficiency and performance of application code.
- Architecting integration of new side-products into the core product.
- Keep products stable, foresee and eliminate roadblocks or potential obstacles.
- Getting involved in product releases, monitoring and hot fixing of the live issues.
- Performing code-review of 10+ peer developers.
- Mentoring junior, interns and other peer developers on various technical and non-technical topics.
- Taking initiative for introducing new tech into team as well as promoting well-known software development principles, industry standards and making best use of what current used language and frameworks offer
- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Framework, JPA/Hibernate, Hazelcast, H2/PostgreSQL, JUnit/Mockito, Liquibase, Thymeleaf, ActiveMQ, Git/GitLab, Jenkins, Graylog, Tomcat, Postman.

27/08/2018 - 21/09/2018 - İzmir, Turkey

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERNSHIP** – YAŞAR BILGI

- Developed a web application called "Dijital.Rehber" which is used in internal of firm to help employees for finds internal phone numbers.
- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, PostgreSQL, Thymeleaf, HTML/CSS/JavaScript/Bootstrap/JQuery

Izmir, Turkey

15/06/2017 – 15/09/2017 – Sandusky/OHIO, United States **LIFE GUARD** – KALAHARI RESORTS&CONVENTIONS

- Taking measures against possible hazards in water park and to intervene in case of danger.
- Raising awareness about the importance of human life.
- Training with customers who want to surf

Sandusky, OHIO, United States

11/07/2016 - 29/07/2016 - İzmir, Turkey

HARDWARE INTERN - DOKUZ EYLÜL UNIVERSITY DEPARTMENT OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES

- To provide all kinds of information processing infrastructure necessary for the functioning of the institution and its existence in the future.
- To provide services in hardware, software, systems, technical service services and training works for institutions.
- In areas where we are responsible, to find solutions to problems as quickly as possible.
- To create a better information systems infrastructure in the future; to provide the necessary support by
  presenting the automation and equipment that will provide continuous improvement and development in
  education, teaching, research and application in accordance with my university.

Izmir, Turkey

**INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SOFTWARE DEVELOPER –** GLM MÜHENDİSLİK ELEKTRİK SİSTEMLERİ İTH. İHR. SAN. VE TİC. A.Ş.

- Creating and editing the required excel tables
- Developed a software which is running on Excel based Visual Basic
- Designed electric panos using AUTOCAD

Izmir, Turkey

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2012 - 09/07/2021 - İzmir, Turkey

BACHELOR DEGREE OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING - Dokuz Eylül University

01/09/2010 - 01/06/2012 - İzmir, Turkey

**COMPLETE HIGH SCHOOL EDUCATION - Bornova Anadolu Lisesi** 

01/09/2008 - 01/06/2010 - Kütahya, Turkey

HIGH SCHOOL - Nafi Güral Fen Lisesi

01/09/2000 - 01/06/2008 - İzmir, Turkey

COMPLETE ELEMENTARY AND SECONDARY EDUCATION - Cumhuriyet İlköğretim Okulu

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): TURKISH

Other language(s):

	UNDERST	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING	
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	B2	B2	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

## PROJECTS

## **Projects that I participated**

## dijital.şirket

- It's an ERP project developed on Spring Framework to supply the firm's all demands . I've developed many areas of this project as a full stack developer.
- Tech stack: Java, Spring Framework, JPA/Hibernate, Hazelcast, H2/PostgreSQL, JUnit/Mockito, Liquibase, Thymeleaf, ActiveMQ, Git/GitLab, Jenkins, REST, Graylog, Tomcat, Apache Camel, Postman, HTML/CSS/ JavaScript/Bootstrap/JQuery.
- dijital.rehber
- I developed this project alone at my internship. This project is a web application that have standart operations e.g. save,update,delete,login...
- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, PostgreSQL, Thymeleaf, HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- o dijital.form
- This project that is also web application is developed by myself to provide for the requirements of another department.
- · Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, PostgreSQL, Mustache, Thymeleaf, HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- e-Transformation
- I participated e-Transformation developments i.e. e-Invoice, e-Archive, e-Despatch, e-Ledger.
- Tech Stack: Java, REST, SOAP, XML/XSLT/JSON, Retrofit.

#### **Educational Projects on University**

#### C#

- Sudoku
- ∘ 2048
- Minefield
- Snake

#### **JAVA**

- Tanks, Cargo Firm Management System
- Student Internship Management System
- Traffic Simulator that prevents traffic jam
- Search Engine

#### C

- Program which converts both XML to JSON and JSON to XML
- Program which implements KD Trees for indexing of multidimensional data
- A secure instant messaging application with using socket programming
- Car monitor that shows current sensor values of working car

#### Java/HTML/CSS/JavaScript/PostgreSQL

Job Search Web Site

## C/C++ with Arduino IDE and Gas sensors

Sensor Network about Indoor Air Qualification

#### **Android Studio**

Captain's Guide Mobile Application

## ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

#### **Organisational skills**

- While working at the business life I have got work experience on multiple projects and various technologies at the same time so I can say that I have got time management and multitasking skills, also I can easily prioritize tasks.
- Taking part in the these projects as group leader, I have acquired good skills of the way how to give the necessary instructions, exert influence and become a leader.
- Integrate into all team situations easily, possessing a personable nature that is open to teamwork and cooperation.
- I own good analytical and creative abilities.
- Finish tasks on time with a reliably high level of quality.

## COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

#### **Communication and interpersonal skills**

- Confident, articulate, great communication skills gained through my experience and working life.
- While studying at the university and working at the business life, I worked on group projects, have learned to convincingly argue my position to the team members, to overcome conflicts and make compromises.
- Through the work as a team member of developer team, internship at different companies, I have improved oratory and presentation skills.